>> Brian Holt: 接下来要做的是 useEffect，我相信是下一个，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Next thing let's go do is
useEffect, I believe is the next one,
嗯， useEffect.
yeah, useEffect.
所以它是在这里有效的
So it's effect.js over here.
>> Brian Holt: 在此，我正在导入 React， useState和 useEffect。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So here, I'm importing
React, useState, and useEffect.
首先我要设定时间每一个
First thing is I'm setting up the time,
which every single
时间是新日期，对，来自 JavaScript的新日期对象。
time this is a new Date, right,
a new Date object from JavaScript.
然后我设置这个 useEffect，这个功能不会马上运行，对吧 ?
Then I set up this useEffect, which this
function is not immediately run, right?
延迟了
It's delayed.
所以它会先完成渲染
So it's gonna finish rendering first, and
安排这事晚点再去好吗
it's scheduling this to be run later,
okay?
所以这是第一次呈现
So then this renders for the first time,
在这里，时间正好是缺省值。
where time is just going to be
the default value right here.
这个 useEffect 还没有在非常，非常第一的情况下运行，好吗 ?
And this useEffect is not yet
run on the very, very first render, okay?
然后，在此完成首次呈示之后，它将调用此 useEffect。
Then after this finish renders for
the first time, it calls this useEffect.
或者说，你提供给这个 " 使用效果 " 的功能好吗 ?
Or rather, the function that you
provided to this useEffect, okay?
在此，它会设置一个新的计时器来再次运行此效果。
And here it sets a new timer
to run this effect again.
对不起，此 setTime 再次出现在
Sorry, this setTime again to a new date in
1000 毫秒好吗
1,000 milliseconds, okay?
这就是它每次都在做的事情。
And so
that's what it's doing every single time.
请注意，这是使用设置超时。
Notice this is using set timeout.
这实际上不是在使用 setInterval，对吗 ?
This not actually using setInterval,
right?
因为每秒钟都在重新渲染
Because it's rerendering
every single one second,
总是安排一个新的超时时间对吧
which is always scheduling a new timeout,
right?
现在，你也可以用 setInterval 做这个，对吧 ?
Now, you could do this with
setInterval as well, right?
但我想向你证明它总是在安排这个，对吧 ?
But I wanted to prove to you that it's
constantly scheduling this, right?
这看起来就像每秒钟都在运行，对吧 ?
And this looks like it's
running every second, right?
因此，它每秒都是这样做的。
So it's predictably
doing this every second.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
>> Brian Holt: 现在注意到没有第二个参数。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Now notice that
this has no second parameter.
这意味着每次出现这种情况
That means that every single
time this render happens,
这会让这事再次发生对吧
it's scheduling this to run again, right?
因此，每次此超时更改都将运行此效果。
So this effect runs every single
time that this timeout changes.
我可以在这里说空话
I can say empty array here.
突然之间，通知停止了更新，对吧 ?
And all of a sudden,
notice that this stopped updating, right?
因为我给了它一个依赖性清单，我说这没有依赖性，所以
Because I gave it a list of dependencies
and I said this has no dependencies, so
只有在我第一次这样做的时候才会这么做
only run this on the very,
very first time that I run this.
这就是它所做的对吧
Which is what it did, right?
> > Brian Holt: 所以现在它只会运行一次
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So
now it's only gonna run once and
永远不会再跑了
never run again.
一旦我再把它取出来
As soon as I take this out again,
通知它会回到每一个时间运行
notice it'll go back to
running every single time.
>> Brian Holt: 现在，我真正应该在此做的是我调用 setTime
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Now, what I really should
do here is you see that I call setTime
就在这里
right here.
根据 React 团队，您应该使此依赖关系，如果
According to the React team, you should
make this a dependency that says if
setTime 更改， >> Brian Holt:
setTime changes,
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Which it won't,
它是这个钩子给你提供的功能
cuz it's a function that's
provided to you by this hook here.
所以这永远不会改变
So this'll never change.
所以，但是根据雷act队，他们还觉得这是一个附属关系，所以
So but according to the React team,
they still think this is a dependency, so
你应该把它放在那儿
you should put it there.
所以我说他们知道他们在干什么，他们写的。
So I say they know what they're doing,
they wrote it.
因此，将 setTime 置于此处作为依赖关系。
So put setTime here as a dependency.
库兹发现这还是有用的也许它不起作用
Cuz notice this still works the way
that should, maybe it doesn't.
>> Brian Holt: 你知道吗 ? 这也不是真的
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: You know what?
That's not true either.
所以应该是时候了，因为时间是这里的应急预案。
So it really should be time,
because time is the contingency here.
>> Brian Holt: 这是正确的。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: That's true.
>> Brian Holt: 在任何情况下，我们都希望它运行每个呈现，因为
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: In any case, we always want
it to run every single render because
这件事就是这么做的
that's what this component does.
所以我就把这个空了
So I would just leave this empty,
actually.
现在，您在这里看到它正在返回一个调用 clearTimeout的函数。
Now, you notice here that it's returning
a function that calls clearTimeout.
因为超时，如果你不清楚，你可能有
Because timeouts, if you don't clear them,
you can potentially have
我有个奇怪的虫子然后我就把它解开了
weird bugs where I have this useEffect
thing, and then I unmount it.
然后就会尝试调用 setTimeout ，或者
And it's then going to try and
call setTimeout, or rather,
在未安装的组件上再次设置时间，这很糟糕，对吗 ?
setTime again on an unmounted component,
and that's bad, right?
所以我现在所做的就是这个运行的时候，它抓住了这个计时器。
So here what I do is anytime that
this runs, it grabs this timer.
如果这事没安装就能清理计时器了对吧
And if this gets unmounted,
it'll clear the timer, right?
因此，此功能将运行，这是清除功能。
So this function will get run,
this is the clean up function.
因此，如果您在此处执行 AJAX 请求，那么可以取消该请求。
So if you're doing AJAX requests here,
you could cancel the request.
如果您正在执行与 jQuery 集成的操作，那么可以清除 RD3 或
If you're doing something like integrating
with jQuery, you could clear up RD3 or
就像这样你可以把所有东西都清理一下
something like that,
you could clear up all that stuff.
这就是你清理的地方
So this is where you
clean up with effects.